Guide to the Alyse Gregory Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers of Others Held by Alyse Gregory, 1897-1950; Series IX; 2.1; (5 boxes)
  - LLEWELYN POWYS PAPERS
    - Diaries
      - Original Diaries
        - Diary, 1929 (Box 72, Folder 1294)
          Contains notes and a few brief entries
        - Diary, 1933 (Box 73, Folder 1295)
      - Transcripts
        - "Diary, LlP, Oct 1908-1909" (2 drafts), 1908 Oct-09 Feb (Box 73, Folder 1296)
          Transcribed AG in 1953, with notes, 1964
        - "A Consumptive's Diary ... Diaries and Journals No. 3", 1909 Nov-10 Apr (Box 73, Folder 1297)
        - "Diary No. 14 (1909)" (2 drafts), 1909 Jan-Dec (Box 73, Folder 1298)
        - "Diary, 1910" (2 drafts), 1910 Jan-Dec (Box 73, Folder 1299-1302)
        - "1911" (2 drafts), 1911 Jan-Dec (Box 73, Folder 1303-1306)
          Transcribed by AG in 1956
        - "Small Red Leather Diary, 1912" (2 drafts), 1912 Jan-May (Box 73, Folder 1307)
        - "Africa Journal", 1913?-18 (Box 73, Folder 1308)
          Transcribed by AG in 1953
        - "Diary, LlP, 1914 ... Diary No. 4" (2 drafts), 1914 May-Dec (Box 73, Folder 1309)
        - "Small Red Diary, No. 12" (2 drafts), 1919 May-Jul (Box 73, Folder 1310)
        - "Diary No. 15" (2 drafts), 1919 Aug-20 Jan (Box 73, Folder 1311)
    - Writings
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, Powys, Llewelyn, Box 33, folders 562-570
      - Essay Transcripts Made by AG and Kenneth Hopkins
        - "The Art of Thomas Hardy", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1312)
        - "The Chesil Beach", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1313)
        - "The First Fall of Snow", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1314)
        - "Green Corners of Dorset", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1315)
        - "Hedgecock and Old Hedgecock Memories" (Box 73, Folder 1316)
        - "Herrick's Fairies", 1933 (Box 73, Folder 1317)
        - "Inland" (Box 73, Folder 1318)
        - "Lodmoor", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1319)
        - "Long Lasting Local Names in the Yeovil District", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1320)
        - "Signs of the Times", 1933 (Box 73, Folder 1321)
        - "The Swannery Bell at Abbotsbury", n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1322)
      - Other Writings
        - Book reviews, clippings, 1923, 1927 (Box 74, Folder 1323)
        - "The Dawn Breakers," essay, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1324)
        - "God," essay, clipping from The New English Weekly, 1933 Jul 13 (Box 74, Folder 1325)
        - Letters to editors, clipping and transcripts by AG, 1919-36, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1326)
        - Somerset Essays, proofreading notes by AG and an unidentified reader, holograph (Box 74, Folder 1327)
        - Unidentified, proofreading notes by John Cowper Powys, holograph, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1328)
        - Other notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1329)
    - Other Llewelyn Powys Papers
      - Chesshire, May. Notebook, holograph, 1937, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1330)
        Presentation inscription from LP
      - Clippings, 1931-44, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1331)
  - EDNA ST. VINCENT MILLAY WRITINGS
    - "Birds Seen From Windows of House at Steepletop," list, holograph (Box 74, Folder 1332)
      With notes by AG
    - "Fog at Daybreak," poem, holograph, corrected, signed, 1934 Apr 16 (Box 74, Folder 1333)
      Appeared in Huntsman, What Quarry as "Impression: Fog Off the Coast of Dorset"
    - "For LP," poem, holograph, signed, 1934 Apr 17 (Box 74, Folder 1334)
      Appeared in Huntsman, What Quarry as "The Ballad of Chaldon Down"
    - Poems from Buck in the Snow, transcribed by LP, holograph, and signed by ESVM (Box 74, Folder 1335)
      Contents: "The Buck in the Snow" "West Country Song" "On First Having Heard the Skylark"
    - Poems from Huntsman, What Quarry?, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1336)
      With notes by AG Contents: "The True Encounter" "The Princess Recalls Her One Adventure" "Short Story" "To a Calvinist in Bali" "To a Young Poet" "Huntsman, What Quarry?" "Sonnet" ("Be sure my coming was a sharp offense") "Sonnet" ("Thou famished grave, I will not fill thee yet") (2 copies)
    - Poems from Wine From These Grapes, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1337-1338)
      Contents: "The Oak Leaves" "The Fawn" "There No Flower" ("In the Grave No Flower") "The Solid Sprite Who Stands Alone" "Spring in the Garden" "Sonnet" ("Time, that renews the tissues of this frame") "Aubade" (2 copies) "Sappho Crosses the Dark River into Hades" (3 copies) "The Leaf and the Tree" "On the Wide Heath" "Apostrophe to Man" "My Spirit Sore From Marching" "Conscientious Objector" "Above These Cares" "How Naked Without a Wall"
      "Epitaph for the Race of Man"; includes: "Have you a townsman somewhere in the crowd" "When Death was young and bleaching bones were few" "O Earth, unhappy planet born to die "When Man is gone and only gods remain "See where Capella with her golden kids" "What rider spurs him from the darkening east" "Now forth to meadow as the farmer goes" "He heard the coughing tiger in the night"
  - JOHN COWPER POWYS WRITINGS
    - Introduction to A Baker's Dozen, by LP, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 74, Folder 1339)
    - "My Brother Llewelyn," essay, drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 74, Folder 1340)
    - "Poem Written by John Cowper Powys at Hotel Seneca in Rochester, N.Y.," typescript, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1341)
      First line: "O sea O sky O planet round"
  - GERTRUDE M. POWYS DIARIES
    - Diaries, 1940-41 (Box 74, Folder 1342)
    - Diaries, 1942-43 (Box 74, Folder 1343)
    - Diaries, 1945-46 (Box 74, Folder 1344)
    - Diaries, 1947-48 (Box 74, Folder 1345)
    - Diaries, 1949-50 (Box 74, Folder 1346)
- Rosemary Manning Papers, 1967-1982; Series X; 0.21; (1 box)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Abrahams, William, 1970 Mar 10 (Box 75, Folder 1347)
    - Ark Press
      See: Taylor, Kim, Box 75, folder 1364
    - Atlantic Monthly Press
      See: Abrahams, William, Box 75, folder 1347
    - Brenan, Gerald, 1970-73 (Box 75, Folder 1348)
    - Costigan, Giovanni, 1973 Mar 8 (Box 75, Folder 1349)
    - de Lima, Agnes, [1970] May 27 (Box 75, Folder 1350)
    - Dyer, Rose, n.y. Mar 27 (Box 75, Folder 1351)
    - Fisher, John (envelope only), 1968 Mar 27 (Box 75, Folder 1352)
    - Gallup, Donald Clifford, 1967-68 (Box 75, Folder 1353)
    - Graves, Richard Perceval, 1982 Jun 10 (Box 75, Folder 1354)
    - Gregory, Alyse, 1965-67, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1355)
    - Hopkins, Kenneth, 1981 Nov 23 (Box 75, Folder 1356)
    - Parkes, Alan, 1967-68 (Box 75, Folder 1357)
    - Penny, Lucy Powys, 1968, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1358)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1967-72 (Box 75, Folder 1359-1360)
    - Powys, William, 1968 Mar 24 (Box 75, Folder 1361)
    - Sewell, Brocard, 1968 Jul 9 (Box 75, Folder 1362)
    - Society of Authors, 1972 Jul (Box 75, Folder 1363)
    - Taylor, Kim, 1973 Sep-Oct (Box 75, Folder 1364)
    - Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1968 Feb-Apr (Box 75, Folder 1365)
    - Wilkinson, Oliver, 1968 Nov 24 (Box 75, Folder 1366)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Clippings, 1967-82, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1367)
    - Notes concerning AG's correspondence (Box 75, Folder 1368)
    - Notes concerning AG's diaries, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1369)
    - Notes concerning LP's correspondence (Box 75, Folder 1370)
    - Other notes, 1973, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1371)
- Oversize, (1 portfolio)
  - Letter from Vere H. Collins to AG (in Series I) (Box Port, Folder 1372)
  - Letters from John Fisher to AG (in Series I) (Box Port, Folder 1373)
  - Printed material relating to The Dial (in Series VII) (Box Port, Folder 1374)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 2, folder 23 (Box 76, Folder 1375)
  - Box 3, folder 44 (Box 76, Folder 1376)
  - Box 3, folder 46 (Box 76, Folder 1377)
  - Box 4, folder 57 (Box 76, Folder 1378)
  - Box 4, folder 60 (Box 76, Folder 1379)
  - Box 4, folder 62 (Box 76, Folder 1380)
  - Box 5, folder 74 (Box 76, Folder 1381)
  - Box 7, folder 100 (Box 76, Folder 1382)
  - Box 9, folder 136 (Box 76, Folder 1383)
  - Box 9, folder 147 (Box 76, Folder 1384)
  - Box 11, folder 173 (Box 76, Folder 1385)
  - Box 12, folder 199 (Box 76, Folder 1386)
  - Box 12, folder 202 (Box 76, Folder 1387)
  - Box 12, folder 209 (Box 76, Folder 1388)
  - Box 13, folder 214 (Box 76, Folder 1389)
  - Box 18, folder 323 (Box 76, Folder 1390)
  - Box 18, folder 324 (Box 76, Folder 1391)
  - Box 18, folder 325 (Box 76, Folder 1392)
  - Box 19, folder 326 (Box 76, Folder 1393)
  - Box 19, folder 327 (Box 76, Folder 1394)
  - Box 19, folder 328 (Box 76, Folder 1395)
  - Box 19, folder 329 (Box 76, Folder 1396)
  - Box 19, folder 330 (Box 76, Folder 1397)
  - Box 19, folder 331 (Box 76, Folder 1398)
  - Box 19, folder 332 (Box 76, Folder 1399)
  - Box 19, folder 333 (Box 76, Folder 1400)
  - Box 19, folder 334 (Box 76, Folder 1401)
  - Box 19, folder 335 (Box 76, Folder 1402)
  - Box 19, fodler 336 (Box 76, Folder 1403)
  - Box 19, folder 337 (Box 76, Folder 1404)
  - Box 19, folder 338 (Box 76, Folder 1405)
  - Box 19, folder 339 (Box 76, Folder 1406)
  - Box 19, folder 340 (Box 76, Folder 1407)
  - Box 20, folder 352 (Box 76, Folder 1408)
  - Box 20, folder 355 (Box 76, Folder 1409)
  - Box 22, folder 393 (Box 76, Folder 1410)
  - Box 24, folder 415 (Box 76, Folder 1411)
  - Box 24, folder 421 (Box 76, Folder 1412)
  - Box 24, folder 422 (Box 76, Folder 1413)
  - Box 24, folder 425 (Box 76, Folder 1414)
  - Box 24, folder 427 (Box 76, Folder 1415)
  - Box 25, folder 429 (Box 76, Folder 1416)
  - Box 25, folder 430 (Box 76, Folder 1417)
  - Box 25, folder 432 (Box 76, Folder 1418)
  - Box 25, folder 433 (Box 76, Folder 1419)
  - Box 25, folder 440 (Box 76, Folder 1420)
  - Box 25, folder 441 (Box 76, Folder 1421)
  - Box 26, folder 444 (Box 76, Folder 1422)
  - Box 26, folder 445 (Box 76, Folder 1423)
  - Box 26, folder 446 (Box 76, Folder 1424)
  - Box 26, folder 449 (Box 76, Folder 1425)
  - Box 26, folder 450 (Box 76, Folder 1426)
  - Box 26, folder 451 (Box 76, Folder 1427)
  - Box 26, folder 455 (Box 76, Folder 1428)
  - Box 27, folder 456 (Box 76, Folder 1429)
  - Box 27, folder 460 (Box 76, Folder 1430)
  - Box 27, folder 461 (Box 76, Folder 1431)
  - Box 27, folder 464 (Box 76, Folder 1432)
  - Box 27, folder 467 (Box 76, Folder 1433)
  - Box 28, folder 472 (Box 76, Folder 1434)
  - Box 28, folder 476 (Box 76, Folder 1435)
  - Box 28, folder 478 (Box 76, Folder 1436)
  - Box 28, folder 480 (Box 77, Folder 1437)
  - Box 28, folder 483 (Box 77, Folder 1438)
  - Box 30, folder 506 (Box 77, Folder 1439)
  - Box 30, folder 512 (Box 77, Folder 1440)
  - Box 30, folder 513 (Box 77, Folder 1441)
  - Box 30, folder 515 (Box 77, Folder 1442)
  - Box 30, folder 516 (Box 77, Folder 1443)
  - Box 30, folder 517 (Box 77, Folder 1444)
  - Box 31, folder 537 (Box 77, Folder 1445)
  - Box 33, folder 563 (Box 77, Folder 1446)
  - Box 33, folder 566 (Box 77, Folder 1447)
  - Box 33, folder 567 (Box 77, Folder 1448)
  - Box 36, folder 622 (Box 77, Folder 1449)
  - Box 36, folder 623 (Box 77, Folder 1450)
  - Box 38, folder 665 (Box 77, Folder 1451)
  - Box 38, folder 667 (Box 77, Folder 1452)
  - Box 38, folder 669 (Box 77, Folder 1453)
  - Box 39, folder 695 (Box 77, Folder 1454)
  - Box 40, folder 700 (Box 77, Folder 1455)
  - Box 40, folder 705 (Box 77, Folder 1456)
  - Box 41, folder 714 (Box 77, Folder 1457)
  - Box 43, folder 750 (Box 77, Folder 1458)
  - Box 43, folder 761 (Box 77, Folder 1459)
  - Box 45, folder 795 (Box 77, Folder 1460)
  - Box 46, folder 799 (Box 77, Folder 1461)
  - Box 46, folder 809 (Box 77, Folder 1462)
  - Box 47, folder 812 (Box 77, Folder 1463)
  - Box 47, folder 814 (Box 77, Folder 1464)
  - Box 50, folder 865 (Box 77, Folder 1465)
  - Box 50, folder 866 (Box 77, Folder 1466)
  - Box 50, folder 870 (Box 77, Folder 1467)
  - Box 51, folder 878 (Box 77, Folder 1468)
  - Box 52, folder 907 (Box 77, Folder 1469)
  - Box 52, oflder 910 (Box 77, Folder 1470)
  - Box 52, folder 911 (Box 77, Folder 1471)
  - Box 53, folder 914 (Box 77, Folder 1472)
  - Box 60, folder 1007 (Box 77, Folder 1473)
  - Box 60, folder 1012 (Box 77, Folder 1474)
  - Box 60, folder 1016 (Box 77, Folder 1475)
  - Box 60, folder 1022 (Box 77, Folder 1476)
  - Box 60, folder 1023 (Box 77, Folder 1477)
  - Box 60, folder 1027 (Box 77, Folder 1478)
  - Box 60, folder 1032 (Box 77, Folder 1479)
  - Box 60, folder 1037 (Box 77, Folder 1480)
  - Box 65, folder 1079 (Box cs, Folder 1481)
  - Box 65, folder 1089 (Box cs, Folder 1482)
  - Box 68, folder 1131 (Box 77, Folder 1483)
  - Box 68, folder 1137 (Box 77, Folder 1484)
  - Box 68, folder 1139 (Box 77, Folder 1485)
  - Box 68, folder 1140 (Box 77, Folder 1486)
  - Box 68, folder 1141 (Box 77, Folder 1487)
  - Box 68, folder 1143 (Box 77, Folder 1488)
  - Box 68, folder 1145 (Box 77, Folder 1489)
  - Box 68, folder 1146 (Box 77, Folder 1490)
  - Box 68, folder 1150 (Box 77, Folder 1491)
  - Box 68, folder 1152 (Box 77, Folder 1492)
  - Box 70, folder 1175 (Box 77, Folder 1493)
  - Box 70, folder 1176 (Box 77, Folder 1494)
  - Box 71, folder 1240 (Box 77, Folder 1495)
  - Box 72, folder 1275 (Box 77, Folder 1496)
  - Box 74, folder 1331 (Box 77, Folder 1497)
  - Box 75, folder 1367 (Box 77, Folder 1498)
- Restricted Fragile Oversize, 1.25; (1 box)
  - Box 4, folder 78 (Box 78, Folder 1499)
  - Box 6, folder 86 (Box 78, Folder 1500)
  - Box 6, folder 95 (Box 78, Folder 1501)
  - Box 24, folder 420 (Box 78, Folder 1502)
  - Box 24, folder 424 (Box 78, Folder 1503)
  - Box 25, folder 431 (Box 78, Folder 1504)
  - Box 25, folder 434 (Box 78, Folder 1505)
  - Box 45, folder 789 (Box 78, Folder 1506)
  - Box 46, folder 804 (Box 78, Folder 1507)
  - Box 46, folder 810 (Box 78, Folder 1508)
  - Box 60, folder 1005 (Box 78, Folder 1509)
  - Box 60, folder 1006 (Box 78, Folder 1510)
  - Box 60, folder 1025 (Box 78, Folder 1511)
  - Box 60, folder 1034 (Box 78, Folder 1512)
  - Box 68, folder 1133 (Box 78, Folder 1513)
  - Box 68, folder 1136 (Box 78, Folder 1514)
  - Box 68, folder 1142 (Box 78, Folder 1515)
  - Box 68, folder 1154 (Box 78, Folder 1516)
  - Box 68, folder 1156 (Box 78, Folder 1517)
  - Box 69, folder 1169 (Box 78, Folder 1518)
  - Box 74, folder 1323 (Box 78, Folder 1519)
  - Box 74, folder 1326 (Box 78, Folder 1520)